Adrien Atallah

AdrienAtallah@gmail.com

Summary:

Advanced physics and mathematics professional with a passion for software/web development, extensive teaching experience and computational skills, including HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript, seeks junior web developer position in a dynamic atmosphere with job growth potential.

Technologies:

Operating Systems: UNIX, Windows, and Mac OS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, R, Fortran 90/95, C++, Java,

Bash Shell

Frameworks/Tools: jQuery, Bootstrap 3.*, Sublime Text, VIM, Git

Other Software: MATLAB, LabVIEW, Mathematica, SolidWorks

3D, AutoCAD, Adobe Photoshop, Premiere, Pro/Engineer, Root Particle Physics Data Analysis

Framework

Education:

Master of Arts San Diego State University (SDSU)

Major: Physics Graduated: May 2015

Internship:

CERN, Geneva, Switzerland

June 2010 – August 2010

- Conducted a study on the signal to noise ratio for the ATLAS pixel detector
- Used ToothPix-ATLAS pixel detector interface to calibrate threshold noise levels
- Utilized CERN Root distribution with Unix to analyze data collected from the ATLAS pixel detector

Bachelor of Science California State University at Long Beach (CSULB)

Major: Physics Graduated: December 2010

Full Stack Web Development Certification Free Code Camp

Expected Completion: October 2016

Academic Honors/Organizations: Society of Physics Students (SPS)

President's List (Fall 2010)

Dean's List (Fall 2005, Spring 2006)

Professional Experience:

Instructor of Mathematics and Physics

September 2015– Present

High Bluff Academy

- Prepare lesson plans and conduct lectures/problem solving workshops for High School level Mathematics and Physics courses
- Tutor and Mentor students in a 1 on 1 setting
- Help develop AP curriculum in Computer Science, Mathematics and Physics

Teaching Associate/Graduate Associate

August 2011– May 2015

San Diego State University

- Prepared course material and lectured for Calculus-based undergraduate physics laboratory courses (Mechanics, Circuits, Electricity and Magnetism)
- Held regular office hours to meet with and help students individually
- Graded work for a graduate level physics course

Faculty Research Member

Physics Department, CSULB

July 2011 – August 2011

- NSF funded computational research in condensed matter physics
- Explored the polarizability and other solid state properties of the new material graphene
- Utilized computational techniques in Fortran

Technical Associate

February 2011 - July 2011

The Premier Landscaping, Fullerton, CA

- Dealt with customers/contractors technical problems over the phone
- Quality control of data entry using company's unique software, FieldComm
- Oversaw team responsible for uploading photos to FTP servers

Mathematics & Physics Tutor

August 2006 – June 2008

Learning Assistance Center, CSULB Campus, CA

- Tutored college students in subjects ranging from basic algebra to advanced vector calculus, with an emphasis on applied calculus for engineering, business, and biology
- Conducted collaborative problem-solving workshops with students
- Held scheduled office hours and met with students for individual appointments

Other Skills & Qualifications:

- Excellent at modeling, utilizing computational techniques to solve physical problems
- Highly proficient in explaining technical concepts to people of all levels of expertise
- Friendly and outgoing; great interpersonal communications skills
- Detail oriented and organized
- Excellent working in a collaborative/group environment
- Quick and efficient at learning any type of new task